<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

 <title>Sangmin Yoon</title>
 <link href="http://localhost:4000/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
 <link href="http://localhost:4000/"/>
 <updated>2025-01-14T11:54:27+09:00</updated>
 <id>http://localhost:4000</id>
 <author>
   <name></name>
   <email></email>
 </author>

 
 <entry>
   <title>GPT 1, 2, 3 and 4</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/2025/01/14/gpt-1-2-3-and-4"/>
   <updated>2025-01-14T00:00:00+09:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/2025/01/14/gpt-1,-2-,3-and-4</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;h3 id=&quot;1-gpt-1&quot;&gt;1) GPT-1&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;GPT-1 introduced a groundbreaking approach to natural language processing by leveraging the power of unsupervised pre-training. This technique involves training a language model on a massive amount of text data without any explicit labels. The resulting model, equipped with a deep understanding of language, can then be fine-tuned on specific tasks with relatively small labeled datasets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;key-differences-from-traditional-supervised-learning&quot;&gt;Key Differences from Traditional Supervised Learning&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Pre-training: GPT-1’s approach starts with a pre-trained model, whereas traditional supervised learning trains a model from random initialization.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Data Efficiency: GPT-1 requires significantly less labeled data for fine-tuning, making it more practical for real-world applications.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Transfer Learning: GPT-1 enables transfer learning, allowing the model to adapt to new tasks with minimal effort.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;how-does-supervised-fine-tuning-work-in-gpt-1&quot;&gt;How does supervised fine-tuning work in GPT-1?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Pre-trained Model: A language model is first trained on a massive corpus of text data. This pre-training step allows the model to learn the statistical properties of language, such as grammar and semantics.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Task-Specific Fine-tuning: The pre-trained model is then adapted to a specific task using a labeled dataset. This involves adding a linear layer to the model and training it on the new task while keeping most of the pre-trained parameters fixed.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Input Transformations: To accommodate various tasks, GPT-1 employs input transformations. For instance, in question answering, the question, context, and answer choices are concatenated into a single sequence.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Objective Function: The model is trained to minimize a combined loss function that includes both a supervised loss for the specific task and an unsupervised loss to preserve the language modeling capabilities.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;2-gpt-2&quot;&gt;2) GPT-2&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;key-advancements-of-gpt-2&quot;&gt;Key Advancements of GPT-2&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;GPT-1 introduced the concept of pre-training a language model on a massive amount of text data and then fine-tuning it on specific tasks.
GPT-2 took this concept to the next level by training an even larger model on a more diverse dataset.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Increased Model Size: GPT-2 employed significantly larger models, allowing for more complex pattern recognition and better generalization.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Unsupervised Multitask Learning: Unlike GPT-1, which relied on supervised fine-tuning for specific tasks, GPT-2 demonstrated the ability to perform a wide range of tasks directly from the pre-trained model, without explicit task-specific training.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Improved Zero-Shot Learning: GPT-2 exhibited remarkable zero-shot learning capabilities, meaning it could perform tasks it had not been explicitly trained on, simply by providing the task as text.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;3-gpt-3&quot;&gt;3) GPT-3&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;GPT-3 represents a significant leap forward in the evolution of large language models, building upon the successes of its predecessors, GPT-1 and GPT-2.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;key-advancements-of-gpt-3&quot;&gt;Key Advancements of GPT-3&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Massive Scale: GPT-3 boasts a significantly larger number of parameters compared to GPT-2, resulting in a dramatic increase in model capacity and computational power.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Enhanced Capabilities: GPT-3 demonstrated impressive abilities in various NLP tasks, including:
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Text generation: Generating human-like text, writing stories, translating languages, and even composing poems.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Question answering: Providing comprehensive and informative answers to a wide range of questions.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Code generation: Writing and debugging code in various programming languages.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Creative content creation: Generating novel content, such as scripts, articles, and even musical pieces.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In-context learning: GPT-3 exhibited remarkable in-context learning capabilities, demonstrating the ability to adapt to new tasks or concepts simply by providing a few examples within the input.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Few-shot learning: GPT-3 achieved impressive results in few-shot learning scenarios, where the model is provided with only a few labeled examples for a new task.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;4-gpt-4&quot;&gt;4) GPT-4&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;GPT-4 represents the latest advancement in the GPT series of large language models, pushing the boundaries of AI capabilities even further.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;key-advancements-of-gpt-4&quot;&gt;Key Advancements of GPT-4&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Enhanced Capabilities: GPT-4 demonstrates significantly improved performance across a wide range of tasks, including:
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Creativity: Generating more creative and innovative text formats, such as poems, code, and scripts.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Problem-solving: Exhibiting enhanced reasoning and problem-solving abilities, including the ability to handle more complex and nuanced tasks.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Safety and Reliability: GPT-4 has been developed with a strong emphasis on safety and reliability, aiming to minimize biases, hallucinations, and harmful outputs.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Multimodality: GPT-4 introduces multimodality, allowing it to accept and process both text and image inputs. This opens up new possibilities for applications such as image captioning, visual question answering, and more.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Advanced In-context Learning: GPT-4 further enhances in-context learning capabilities, allowing it to learn and adapt to new tasks with even fewer examples.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 

</feed>
